### **MEERAJ SHAH**

P.O.Box 49887-00100, Nairobi, Kenya Mobile:+254(0)738752983 , E-mail: meerj.shah@superfoamltd.com

#### PROFILE

I am a graduate in Economics from the University of Bristol. I have over fourteen years work experience in areas of Agriculture, Manufacturing, banking and the service industry. I possess strong analytical skills that enable me to make well thought out decisions and have good communication skills that allow me to deal with a wide range of people. I have great dedication and commitment to complete any given task and am confident enough to add value to whatever projects that I take on and I am open to learn any new ideas. I can adapt to new cultures & environment. I am a keen sportsman and traveller.

#### **EDUCATION**

Degree September 2002- June 2005 The University of Bristol

Bsc (Hons) Economics

A Levels September 1999-July 2001 Brighton College, Brighton

3 A Levels - Mathematics with Mechanics (A), Physics (B) and Economics (B).

O Levels July 1999 Mombasa Academy, Mombasa, Kenya

Mathematics (A), Pure Mathematics (B), English (A), Chemistry (B), Biology (A), Physics (A),

Geography (B), Economics (A), French (B)

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

### <u>Technical production manager - Superfoam ltd (2018- present)</u>

• Responsible for product development and formulations

### Director, A-One Plastics Ltd, Kenya ( January 2009- present )

Largest recycler in East and Southern Africa till 2018 (plastic ban implemented in Kenya)

## Director & Founder, Digital packaging Innovations Holdings Ltd, Kenya (July 2016 - present)

- Oversaw the construction of a new 85,000 square feet custom built factory in Ruiru built to the highest ISO and BRC standards
- Instrumental in bringing the first HP Indigo 20,000 digital printer to Africa
- Secured 4.7 million Euros funding from a leading European machine manufacturer in Germany over five years at less than 2% interest rate per anum.

## Assistant General Manager, Super Foam ltd, Kenya (November 2012-October 2018)

- Responsible for purchasing and installing a new foaming machine from Norway in 2014
- Managed substantial growth in the business turnovers
- Dealt with major suppliers for raw material purchase
- Responsible for growth, Strategy and expansion plans
- General Manager, Addis Poly plc, Ethiopia (July 2005 to December 2008)
- Set up and run a successful foam manufacturing plant In Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
- Was a market leader with prominent brands

# ACHIEVEMENTS, LEADERSHIP AND POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

- Senior positions in Various companies
- · Keen golfer playing of handicap 16
- Seasoned traveler
- Keen Hiker and have successfully climbed Mt Kenya and Mt Kilimanjaro as well as hikes in New Zealand, Slovenia, Croatia and others.
- 2002-2005: Various positions held in University of Bristol Societies , including the treasurer of the Soul society
- 1999: Entered Brighton College as a full boarder on an Academic Scholarship.
- House prefect at Brighton College
- Various Sports teams at all levels of Education

#### OTHER SKILLS

- Use of accounting software Quickbooks, tally, SAP
- · Proficient in Microsoft Excel, Word, Microsoft Outlook and various computer software
- Involved in various other investments and opportunities including high end safari lodges in Tanzania

### LANGUAGES

English, Gujarati, Swahili, French (Very basic)

#### REFERENCES

Mike Fischer

CEO

Super Foam Ltd

Tel: +2540716181818

Email: mike.fischer@superfoamltd.com

Jaganathan Sathyanarayanan

CEO, DPI Holdings,

Tel: +254737888818

Email: j.sathya@dpiholdings.com

Other References available on request